You've made it. We're here.
لقد أنجزتم ذلك. نحن هنا.
This is the lesson where we start to actually
هذا هو الدرس الذي نبدأ خلاله حقًا في
control the document object model with Javascript.
التحكم في نموذج كائن المستند (DOM) باستخدام Javascript.
In the last lesson, we learned about the DOM,
في الدرس السابق، لقد تعرفنا على DOM،
the Document Object Model,
نموذج كائن المستند،
and in it we learned a few ways to select items in the DOM, ".getElementByID()",
وتعلمنا خلاله بعض طرق تحديد العناصر في DOM وهي ".getElementByID()"
".getElementsByClassName()", the ".querySelector()", and a few others.
و".getElementsByClassName()" و".querySelector()" وبعض الطرق الأخرى.
And we looked at the Node and Element interfaces and the list of
ولقد اطلعنا على واجهات Node وElement وقائمة تتضمن
properties and methods that they pass on to their individual elements.
خصائص وأساليب تمررها إلى عناصرها الفردية.
Now like I said at the beginning,
الآن، مثلما قلت في البداية،
this is the lesson we'll use Javascript and DOM methods to create,
سنستخدم في هذا الدرس أساليب Javascript وDOM لإنشاء
delete, and manipulate DOM elements.
عناصر DOM وحذفها ومعالجتها.
While working through this content,
أثناء عملنا خلال هذا المحتوى،
you'll start to gain an understanding of
ستبدؤون في فهم
the real power of combining JavaScript and the DOM.
القوة الحقيقية للجمع بين JavaScript وDOM.
If you can't tell already, it's really exciting.
إن لم يمكنكم الإخبار بالفعل، فإنه أمر مثير حقًا.
Now before we dive right in though,
والآن قبل أن نتعمق في الأمر،
we need to download the project that we use for the rest of the course.
نحتاج إلى تنزيل المشروع الذي استخدمناه لبقية الدورة التدريبية.
Okay, you ready? Good. Let's get started.
حسنًا، هل أنتم مستعدون؟ حسنًا. دعونا نبدأ.